both a citizen of Moldova and a citizen of
и гражданин Молдовы и гражданин
Transnistria Yes, from your speeches
Приднестровья Да есть из ваших речей
the state of Moldova Yes oppresses the residents of the
государство Молдова Да угнетает жителей
state of Transnistria, that is, in
государства Приднестровья то есть в
your person, you, as a citizen of Moldova,
вашем лице вы как гражданин Молдовы
through your representatives In power,
через своих представителей Во власти
oppresses yourself as a resident of
угнетает себя же как жителя
Transnistria I
Приднестровья Я правильно
understood correctly Good evening Hello Well, I
понял Добрый вечер Здравствуйте Ну я
know you are a blogger Yes  I’m a blogger
знаю Вы блогер Да я блогер
and I don’t know you You’re not a blogger Well, no,
а я вас не знаю Вы не блогер Ну нет
of course, what the hell is it that bloggers
конечно какой блом таким что блогеры
Some specifically vintage style
Некоторые специально винтажный стиль
do what you think  I also have nano
делать что думаете У меня тоже нано
cabinets like this, I found the walls, hung
такие шкафы стоят Т нашл стенки повесил
it up, support the special operation, well, I’m from Transnistria, you know, take it off with me, well, first of all, I remember you, you were sitting on a bench, rolling around, yes, yes, the ladies
сидели на лавочке катались да да дамы с
were talking to me, no, I’m supporting
ми общались Не ну я поддерживаю потому
because  we had such a situation in our system,
что у нас в стро была ну такая ситуация
so we Well, soon there won’t be a situation, I
поэтому нас Ну скоро не будет ситуации я
remember you, you should have talked
по помню вас вы мне го ты бы пообщался
to Uncle Slava there  with someone Like
Там с дяди Славой там ещё с кем-то Типа
you and I talked for about an hour then and
мы с вами где-то час общались тогда и
this Everything will be fine in the mood
этот Всё нормально у настро будет
Rossi look we talked if I'm not
Росси смотри мы общались если я не
mistaken it was summer Well, something like that
ошибаюсь это было лето Ну да что-то так
Moscow wasn't built right away
Москва не сразу
and it didn't pour right away yeah So
строилась и полилась не сразу да Так что
I  I just remember what we were talking about, yes,
я помню просто о чём мы говорили да там
you would have Timi now, the corridor to
у вас бы Тими сейчас коридор до
Transnistria is shorter, yes Since then,
Приднестровья короче да С тех пор и
Kherson and in short, and that’s it, yes Well, that means it
Херсон и короче и всё да Ну значи так
has to be while someone’s foot is still there  in the camera,
надо пока там чья-то нога ещё в камере
the heel is yours
пятка это ваша
and I think that you are Yes, that’s all I was and I
и я думаю что вы Да всё я я и то и
was surprised I think that you wouldn’t have gotten out of it like that I
удивился думаю что вы так не выкрутились
think maybe you somehow didn’t understand there
бы думаю может вы как-то непонятно там
Maybe I should tell you So before
понял Может вам надо скажу Так что пред
Nestro there will never be Moldova, there
нестро никогда не будет Молдовой никогда
will never be Romania and  not Romania will be
Румынии будет нет и не Румыния будет
Romania Romania will be Romania maybe
Румыния Румыния будет румынией возможно
Moldova will be Moldova but under Nestro it will
Молдова будет Молдовой но при нестро
never be Moldova I’ll tell you this
никогда не будет Молдовой я тебе вот се
Look people don’t want Russia Russia
скажу Смотри люди не хотят Россия Россия
will lose in Ukraine Russia  will fall apart into
проиграет в Украине Россия развалится на
independent states Ukraine will return
независимые государства Украина вернёт
Crimea Donetsk Lugansk Moldova, with the help of
Крым Донецк Луганск Молдова с помощью
international peacekeepers, will establish
миротворцев международных установит
control in Transnistria
контроль в Приднестровье
so all these Russian military men will run away And
так российские эти все военные убегут А
with the rest everything will be fine and
с остальными всё будет нормально и
that’s it Well, we’ll meet you when Well,
всё Ну мы встретимся с вами ког Ну так
you still don’t live in Moscow
вы всё равно же не при вы в Москве
yes, well, I’m going, well, you live in Moscow
да Ну я езжу Ну а то вы живёте в Москве
or you live in
или живёте в
everything you see, people like you are leaving
всё видите Такие как вы по уезжаете из
Transnistrian like me, I'm Russian Well,
приднестровские как я я русский Ну вот и
yes, all the Russians are leaving. And that means to me And that
Да вот все русские уеду А мне значит А
means there's no place for me, but there. Well, you're
мне значит не место да там А ну так Вы
leaving, look, you're leaving
же сами уезжаете смотрите Вы же уезжаете
for Moscow, you're already a Moskvich, so I
в Москву уехали вы уже Москвич так я
left, so I'm No, I'm not a Moskvich.  I
уехал так я Нет я не Москвич У меня даже
don’t even have Russian citizenship. You’ll
русского гражданства нету Вы же
tell me what you have, and you have a
расскажешь что у вас есть а у вас
Ukrainian passport, you said yes, in
украинский паспорт вы говорили да
my opinion, no, I don’t have a Moldovan one, no, you
по-моему нет у меня молдавский нене вы
said that you have  Ukrainian
говорили что у вас есть украинский
passport to travel that I had
паспорт чтобы ездить что это было у меня
Ukrainian No I have a Moldovan
украинского Нет у меня молдавский
passport Moldavian or And this is through
паспорт молдавский или А это через
Ukraine you went to a
Украину вы ездили в
Transnistrian passport if you
приднестровский паспорт если вы
Transnistria
Преднестровье
[music] will
[музыка]
never be Moldova but
никогда не будет Молдовой но молдавский
I took a Moldovan passport I am a citizen
паспорт я взял Я гражданин
Yes Well, what am I  I’m not against
есть Да Ну а что Я же не я же не против
Moldova, but just let them, no matter how they do
Молдовы но просто Пускай они ну как бы
n’t put pressure on our people, so
не людей не прессует наших так заче
why do you take a passport of another
зачем вы берёте паспорт другого
state, a passport from a state that is
государства паспорт государства которое
putting pressure on yours?
прессует ваших
people Well, why should I sit sit there?
людей Ну а что мне сидеть сидеть там нет
Okay okay When will it be, when will
Хорошо о'кей Когда будет когда будет
Transnistria be in Russia, I will have the
Преднестровье России у меня будет
opportunity to go anywhere with another
возможность куда угодно едить другим
passport, if I refuse the Moldovan one, they
паспортом если я откажусь от молдавского
took the Moldavian passport Yes, you are a citizen of
взяли паспорт Молдовы Да вы гражданин
Moldova, that’s how people
Молдовы так это делают кто люди сами
do it themselves. I understand correctly  who elects
дела Я правильно понимаю кто избирает
power in Moldova citizens mo
власть в Молдове граждане мо
Yes look I understand correctly that you
Да смотрите я я правильно понимаю что вы
as a citizen of Moldova uh oppress
как гражданин Молдовы ээ угнетает себя
yourself as a citizen of Transnistria
же как гражданина Приднестровья
Yes I know Well look you
Да знаю Ну смотри у вас
have a passport  citizen of Moldova and have a
есть паспорт гражданина Молдовы и есть
passport of a citizen of Transnistria, yes
паспорт гражданина Приднестровья да Ну
Well, and even Russian or Russian, well, it
да ещё и русский или русского нету ну
will be, but I’m not doing it yet, no Yes,
будет но я пока не делаю пока нет Да вот
look, you know how there is a
смотри у вас вы так знаете как вот есть
two-faced Janus, there was such a deity But I
двуликий Янус было такое божество А это
don’t remember what your name is Well  I
вот не помню как вас зовут Ну я на трёх
will sit on three chairs Yes, no, but for now on
стульях буду сидить Да нет по пока на
two, that is, you are sitting at the same time as a
двух то есть сидите вы одновременно и
citizen of Moldova and a citizen of
гражданин Молдовы и гражданин
Transnistria Yes, from your speeches
Приднестровья Да есть из ваших речей
the state of Moldova Yes, it oppresses the inhabitants  the
государство Молдова Да угнетает жителей
state of Transnistria, that is, in
государства Приднестровья то есть в
your person, you are a citizen of Moldova
вашем лице вы как гражданин Молдовы
through your representatives. In power, he
через своих представителей Во власти
oppresses himself as a resident of
угнетает себя же как жителя
Transnistria. I understood correctly, I
Приднестровья Я правильно понял
know,
зна
yes, I don’t
так да я не
deepen it again,
углубляют ещё раз получается
why am I just not going to fight to
зачем я просто я не пойду воевать
conquer, now it’s not provo, I don’t
завоевать вот сейчас не прово вот я не
understand  So you say that Moldova is
понимаю Вот вы говори что Молдова там
oppressive there and something like Transnistria is
угнетает да что-то там Приднестровья там
also there, and I have to refuse the
ещ А я должен отказываться от
Moldavian rook or
молдавского грачем его
whatever  you are just using
вли что вы за просто используете
citizenship, there are parasites on the state of
гражданство есть паразити на государстве
Moldova, no. Well, well, look, if
Молдова нет А хорошо А смотрите если
the state of Moldova treats me so badly,
государство Молдова так плохо относится
and I don’t know why they
а я не знаю зачем
issue them, well, look, if they
выдают ну так смотри если они они
would like it the other way around, let’s not
наоборот хотели бы а давайте им не будем
issue them passports, let them
выдавать паспорта пусть они вообще
not go anywhere at all  they will come out Well, yes, why
никуда нафиг не выйдут А ну да А почему
are there and they are bad? Yes, why are they issuing them, I
есть и они плохие Да почему они выдают я
don’t know why they are issuing them so that there are
не знаю почему выдают для того чтобы на
more citizens like there on the
было больше граждан типа там на
territory of Moldova, so that in the territory of the
территории Молдавии чтобы на территории
construction site they
стро с т сем
specially distribute passports  in
за специально раздаёт паспорта в
Transnistria in order to then enter
Приднестровье для того чтобы потом войти
And I understand correctly that by taking
А и я правильно понимаю что вы взявши
the passport of a citizen of Moldova, you are
паспорт гражданина Молдовы вы вот эти
bringing NATO troops in the future. Yes, it’s
получается приводите в будущем войска
correct to enter the territory of Transnistria. Perhaps, but we have
правильно Возможно но у нас же живут в
Moldovan citizens living in Transnistria who do not
Приднестровье гражда Молдовы которые не
agree with the policies that  Nowadays,
согласны с ну с политикой которая сечас
this state is becoming more fashionable in
происходит модне это государство по
your opinion, but citizens of Transnistria live there, it
вашему да то там живут граждане
turns out not only Well, look, the
получается не только Ну смотрите
Ukrainians are Moldovans, not by no, I’m
украинцы молдаване не по не я же говорю
not talking about  nationality And about
не про национальность А про
citizenship, if a Chechen lives there, he’s a
гражданство если чеченец там живёт он
citizen of Transnistria, for example. Well,
там гражданин Приднестровья например Ну
they don’t have to, you can
у них нет не обязательно ты можешь
come there, for example, with, say,
приехать туда например с допустим
some kind of passport with an American Yes, a
каким-то паспортом с американским Да
passport, get a temporary permit. Well, that’s
паспортом получить временное вид Ну ВН
all and live
всё и жить
with an American passport, get an Ilu
приме с американским паспортом прие Илу
residence permit  come And here we have
вид жительство прид А у нас там у нас
a lot of foreigners and
там много живут стати иностранцев и
Aryan Americans living there. But damn, this is really
американцы арикан А вот блин это реально
interesting, but why do Americans
интересно а вот Для чего американцы
come to Transnistria to live in the PM
приезжают в Приднестровье жить на ПМ
because  that life there is good life is good even I
потому что там жи хоро жиз хороша даже
live there Yeah That is, I got it right
живу там Ага То есть получа я правильно
Understanding that people from the United States of
Поня что люди из Соединённых Штатов
America fly across the ocean to
Америки летят через океан для того чтобы
live in
жить в
Transnistria, watch the video, even on the
Приднестровье посмотрите видео даже в
Internet there are, yeah, a lot of such
интернете есть ага много таких
Americans Well, I saw three people
американцев Ну я видел человека три
exactly from the video  I’m showing, but there are
точно именно по видео показываю но есть
also Africans, there are three people in all of
и африканцы человека человека три на всё
Transnistria, there are Americans. Yes, I don’t
Приднестровье есть американцы Да я не
know, but I saw only three; they showed,
знаю но я видел только троих показывали
maybe they’re still there, no wait, they’re
быть все же они все же нет подождите они
still there. According to Dawa’s interview, how about  you
все же Согласно интервью Дава А как вы
think why Americans come here is
думаете ради чего американцы приезжаю
what attracts them there. Well, look.
вот что там их привлекает Ну смотрите
For example, I don’t remember about the Americans, what’s the
Например я не помню про американце какая
situation there, someone comes as a
у там ситуация кто-то приезжает
fitness trainer, he got a job with us as a
фитнес-тренером он у нас устроился
fitness trainer, Africans, an African woman. She
фитнес-тренер африканцы африканка Она
says to you, Americans, Africans
говорит у васде вот американцы африканцы
believe that they are coming  in Transnistria Yes
верят что приезжают в Приднестровье Да
no Why do Africans live with us?
нет А почему африканцы живут у нас
Because they say that the climate is
потому что говорят что ва климат
more or less normal, the situation will somehow give us the opportunity to
более-менее нормальный возможность
escape to Europe.
вырваться в Европу хоть как-то даста
But from America, I
обстановка А вот из Америки вот я
really think the man is sitting  in
реально вот думаю Человек сидит в
San Francisco So damn, I
сан-франциско Так блин я сейчас
'll try to find a video now, of course. No, I
постараюсь найти конечно видео Нет я
believe that there is one video,
верю что есть какое-то одно видео
for example, in Moscow, someone might
например в Москву там там кто-то может
have moved to Nizhny Kurany, to Yakutia, maybe
переехал в Нижних куранах в Якутию может
someone will also move alone, here's a
тоже кто-то переехать один вот
crazy person, well, that's it  so that they come
сумасшедший Да ну вот так чтобы ехали
en masse Well, I don’t understand at all Well,
массово Ну вообще не понимаю Ну пока ещё
not yet en masse, well, someone comes to us
не массово ну кто-то приезжает к нам
because, well, I don’t know why I don’t know
потому что ну я не знаю почему я не знаю
why this is right, I don’t know
почему вот это правильно я не знаю
at all Well, what attracts them there?
вообще Ну что их что их там притягивает
I don’t understand Look, there’s a man
Ну я не понимаю Смотри вот есть человек
from San Francisco, the climate in Moldova
с сан-франциско вот ему климат в Молдове
and the climate in Transnistria there in the
и климат в Приднестровья там в
Chernivtsi region are almost the same, it’s
Черновицкой области почти одинаковый
true
правда
yes yes That’s what he flies to
у да да Вот что он именно летит в
Transnistria, they go to Transnistria and
приднестровский едут в Приднестровья и
there through the service they receive a Moldovan
там через службу получают молдавский
passport so that they can travel  it’s
паспорт чтобы могли ездить куда угодно
not so easy to get it anywhere, well, it’s
не так просто получить его ну он там
great there, how much do I think, 250,000 euros,
забашта ну сколько по-моему 250.000 евро
in my opinion? Well, what for  an American 250,000
по-моему Ну что для американца 250.000
euros for the opportunity to travel anywhere with a passport.
евро ради возможности ездить по паспорту
Yes, why
куда угодно Да зачем у него американский
does he have an American passport, that’s what I’m saying and he
паспорт есть вот вот вот я к тому и он
comes to us because I don’t know, he’s
приезжает к нам потому что не знаю он
opening some kind of business there. Even here, well,
там бизнес какой-то открывает Даже у нас
I don’t know what his is.  business in the
ну я не знаю что его А какой бизнес в
Dniester region to open a cafe cafe Yeah I
днестром открывать кафешку кафешку Ага
understand, that is, uh
понял то есть ээ
cafe Well, what is it, ask him
кафешку Ну что это это у него спроси
why when I just didn’t, I just figured out the
почему при Я просто не я просто прикинул
purchasing opportunity, for example, of a
покупательную возможность например
person in Transnistria Yes, how long is
человека в Приднестровье Да что сколько
he there?  this American owes money to the cafe
он там той кафешке должен на паха этот
Yes, in order to recoup not four
американец Да чтобы отбить не четыре
grand bucks a month, I don’t know
штуки баксов каких-то в месяц не зна
Yes, I don’t know, it’s
Да не в курсе
cool, I don’t know Well, some
прикольно не знаю Ну приезжали какие-то
people came Yes, I understood to open Well, look, we
люди Да понял открывать Ну смотри мы
talked then in the summer Yes, now
тогда летом Общались Да теперь уже
Kherson is no longer in Russia I  I think the next
Херсона нет в России я думаю в следующий
time we meet, it would be cool
раз когда встретимся было бы прикольно
if Transnistria was already completely
чтобы уже Приднестровье было полностью
and you will go to
и воевать будет вы поедете
fight, I don’t want to be honest, you
воевать я не хочется честно говоря Вы
will sit over there in Moscow  and that
будете сидеть вон в Москве и вот ту
heel which is Rock and no wait And I
пятку которая Скала а нет подождите А я
have to go shorter I'm not saying
должен поехать короче Уменя Я не говорю
that I should you say people will stand up I'm
что должен вы говорите люди встанут Я
asking Who will stand up you will stand up you are
спрашиваю Вот кто встанет вы встанете вы
like that No well I won't stand up because I have
такие Нет ну не встану потому что у меня
no experience well everything and others like that and
опыта нету ну всё и другие такие и
others  still me and I
другие таки меня а я
stand up there is someone there is someone And that’s
встать там есть кому там есть кому И вот
exactly everyone That’s who is sitting in
вот вот именно каждый Вот кто сидит в
Moscow Yes he left Transnistria Yes there is
Москве Да уехал с приднестровской Да там
someone there to fight they will stand up AT It’s
есть кому воевать они встанут АТ Это
bad that E  And it’s bad that a person
плохо что Е А это плохо что человек
wants to live No, no, didn’t you think that
хочет жить Нет не А вы вы не думали что
if Russian troops disappeared from there,
если пропадёт российские войска оттуда
no one would get involved in
так вообще никто не полезет в пряга из
Transnistria and everyone would live normally
Приднестровье и все нормально будут жить
and they would live normally Nothing that Nothing
и нормально будут жить Ничего что Ничего
that first when Moldova attacked and
что сначала когда Молдова напала да
our Russians came out  Well, when Moldova
вышли русские наши Ну когда Молдова
attacked Well, tell me when Moldova attacked
напала Ну расскажи когда Молдова напала
In ninety In the ninety-second year in
В девяносто В девяносто втором году в
what ninety-second on June 19 of the
каком девяносто втором де 19 июня
ninety-second year  listen, you have the
девяносто второго года слушай э у вас
Soviet army was the
Советская армия стояла вот та
fourteenth or whatever army was there
четырнадцатая или какая армия стояла там
Chen's army was there but they didn't interfere
Чена армия стояла там но они не влазить
at all with the first president of
вообще в не влазит первым президентом
Transnistria Smirnov Smirnov Where is he
Приднестровья Смирнов Смирнов Откуда он
from, where do I know from someone
родом откуда я знаю вот с кого-то
Sakhalin or that he was Russian Well  so
Сахалина или что русский он Побыл Ну так
I think he was in, in my opinion, in the
я же кажу смот он Побыл в по-моему во
PTO Ilin came to Transnistria Yes, and
ВОМ Илин приехал в Приднестровье Да и
after 2 years it started like  separatism to
через 2 года начались типа сепаратизм
do this and he was elected like this
это делать и его избрали типа этим
president Yes, a man who was born
президентом Да человека который родился
somewhere on Sakhalin Russian Yes, they sent him here,
где-то на Сахалине русский Да его сюда
in short, they did what was normal
прислали вот короче сделали че нормально
Now in Moldova, the President of Romania is the ultimate
Сейчас в Молдове Президент Румынии преде
citizen of Romania, the President of
ой гражданин Румынии президент
Moldova, fashionable niya This is the
Молдовы модовая ния Это один и тот же
same people
самый народ
Yes, Romanians  they hate Moldovans, look,
Да румыны ненавидят молдован смотри
they hate, they hate, they’ll figure it out,
ненавидят ненавидят они уже разберутся
it’s one and the same people, they just
это один и тот же самый народ просто
formed into separate states
образовались в отдельные государства
because of historical reasons  Moldova believes
из-за исторических нет Молдова счита
Moldova believes that in short it’s Let the
Молдова считают что короче это Пусть
Moldovans with runes decide there alone, it’s
молдаване с рунами решают там один мне
not important to me now, so I can
сейчас не принципиально вот я могу
speak because it turns out that the
говорить потому то есть получается
Russians made Transnistria, the Russians
русские сделали Приднестровье русские
made Abkhazia, the Russians made the so-
сделали Абхазию русские сделали так
called North Ossetia Yes, the Russians
называемую северную Осетию Да русские
made this DPR LPR Crimea Russians
сделали вот этот ДНР лнр Крым русски
Well, they A  why is this because people
Ну они А почему так Потому что люди
die from
умирают из
Russians In short only from Russians Yes
русских Короче только из русских Да
they die Yes only from Russians and Americans
умирают Да только из русски а американцы
White fluffy white
Белы пушисты белые
fluffy Clearly Americans  help us
пушисты Понятно американцы помогают нам
fight the Russians Well, logically they are
воевать с русскими Ну логично они
white Cool And you don’t like the
белые Прикольно А а вы так не любите
Americans so much Yes, what they did in Iraq is
американцев Да а то что они в Ираке
fine I say You don’t like the
сделали нормально я говорю Вы не любите
Americans yes
американцев да
No I don’t understand politics No, that
Нет я политику это не понимаю Не ну то
is, you don’t like the Americans As I
есть вы американцев не любите Я так
understand it  I said that I don’t
понимаю я сказал что я политику не
support politics, I’m just saying, well, what about the
поддерживаю я вот просто ну а что насчёт
beginning about Iraq, I’m looking at
си нач насчёт Ирака я с я смотрю Вот
our countries, so I wasn’t in Syria in Iraq,
наши страны так я не был в Сирии в Ираке
well, that’s far from me, but we’re looking at the
ну это от меня далеко но мы смотрим
post-Soviet space, the Americans
постсоветское пространство американцы
didn’t make war here, I  I'm watching  Americans,
тут войны не делали я смотрю американцы
on the contrary, the
наоборот
war made Russia Americans helped to
война сделала Россию американцы помогали
develop Even they fed Russia with
развиваться Даже даже Россию кормили
Bush's legs, they helped so that Russia would not
ножками Буша помогали чтобы Россия не
die from the head to feed everyone, in short,
сдохла с голову всех закормить короче
completely As they say, the curtains came in So
совсем Как говорится это зашли шторы Вот
listen, look, fell for
так и слушай смотри повелись на ножке
Bush's legs Here you are now in Moscow,
Буша Вот вы вы сейчас в Москве
yes, let's say, look  let's do this
да да допустим вот смотри давай так
uh Why do Americans live better than
ээ Почему американцы живут лучше чем
Russians the better they live with wallpaper in the closet
россияне чем лучше живут шкафом обоями
they also have this they also have this
у них тоже такое есть тоже такое есть
I can't help but laugh come on
вот я не могу не ржать давай вот
seriously what year is this  Laugh Yes
серьёзно какого года это Посмейся Да
Laugh I just laughed the previous one there
Посмейся Я просто смеялся предыдущий там
was really funny there was no simplicity You will
реально смешно было нет простоты будешь
laugh it won’t offend me No I’m not
смеяться меня это не обидит Да не я
laughing not to offend in order to
смеюсь не для того чтобы обидеть для
shake I can’t because with the
того чтобы пожать не могу потому что с
previous one I really laughed there the guys
предыдущим там на смеялся реально пацаны
were funny what’s annoying you look at me  it does
были чем тебя напрягает смотри меня он
n’t bother me. I just don’t understand when
не напрягает Я просто не понимаю когда
people talk about welfare.
люди говорят что там про благосостояние
And so on and so Russia is a state that
И так дальше так вот Россия государство
has oil gas gold
в котором есть там нефть газ золото
diamonds. Why is the standard of living of people in
алмазы Да почему уровень жизни людей в
Russia less than that of people in the same country?  In the Czech Republic,
России меньше чем людей в той же Чехии
for example, or in Lithuania, today is
например или в Литве вот сегодня День
Lithuania's Independence Day, one of the biggest
независимости Литвы один из в ВОМ году е
transports of the year Why are people in Lithuania,
провоз Почему люди в Лит
Lithuania, not far from Moscow, and people
Литва недалеко от Москвы так и люди
live better than you?
живут лучше чем Вот
I guess I have my own opinion on
вы Наверно я у меня есть сво мнение по
this matter. Well, there is no gas in Lithuania
этому поводу Ну с вот в Литве нет газа
oil diamonds Yes, because
нефти алмазов Да потому что
this is why Russia is supposedly
этот того что Почему Россия там якобы
worse there somewhere, life in some moments is no
хуже где-то живёт в каких-то моментах не
worse than in
хуже чем в
America the better
Америке чем лучше
Yes, I don’t know, I haven’t been to America Okay,
Да не знаю я не был в Америке Хорошо
let’s look at Lithuania  Compare, I was in Lithuania
давай вот Литва вот Сравни вот в Литве
Yes, I haven’t been anywhere, neither in Lithuania nor in
был Да я не был нигде ни в Литве ни в
America, wait anywhere. That is, you were
Америке нигде подожди То есть ты был
only in Transnistria in Moldova and in
только в Приднестровье в Молдове и в
Russia and Ukraine you passed through Italy France
России и Украину проезжал Италия Франция
Finland Oh good, let’s
Финляндия О хорошо Вот давай Финляндия
take Finland not far away, Finland is just people
возьмём недалеко Финляндия как раз люди
in Finland and  people in Russia where they live better
в Финляндии и люди в России где лучше
Damn, how can I tell by walking
Блин ну как я могу сказать по вот ходя
around the city Well, walking around the city Well,
по городу Ну вот ходя по городу Вот
okay, so where
хорошо давай так где
uh, better cities in Finland or in Russia,
ээ лучше города в Финляндии или в России
well, in Russia, there are also beautiful cities,
ну В России тоже красивые города
infrastructure, cleanliness, sidewalks, level
инфраструктура чистота тротуары уровень
There, I didn’t like the bike paths in
Там велодорожки мне не понравилось в
Italy, it was just not like
Италии был вообще просто не вот
Finland, come on, here we are now so that we
Финляндию давай вот мы сейчас чтобы мы
don’t jump from here to Finland, here’s
не прыгали из вот Финляндию вя вот
Finland So you’re in Finland Where  if I were
Финляндия Так ты в Финляндии Где бы был
in Finland in Finland I was at the airport and
в Финляндии в Финляндии я был аэропорт и
at the train station and at otherwise in Finland you were
на вокзале и на а то в Финляндии ты был
only seeing the airport and train station then you are in
только видел аэропорт и вокзал то ты в
Finland  wasn’t Well, yes, the station Well, not the
Финляндии не был Ну да вокзал Ну не
station I mean, there was a little passage there, but
вокзал То бишь там проходил немножко но
Well, as usual, the same thing that you got out in St.
Ну как обычно то же самое что ты вышел в
Petersburg from there went to the village, I understood, yes, that
Питере с там пошёл пос я понял да то
is, if there was only a station, but not like
есть если был только вокзал да не как
I’m just seeing that people are here for
Просто я смотрю что вот люди вот для
me  a mystery Yes, why does Russia, with such
меня загадка Да Почему Россия с такими
resources, not live as richly as countries
ресурсами так не живёт богато как страны
without resources,
без ресу
or maybe because it, as they
а может быть потому что она как
say, is taking over some countries? Yes,
говорится захватывает какие-то страны Да
there are territories and so on, and
там и так далее территории и
maybe that’s where it all goes. Look, let’s
возможно туда это всё ну куда Вот смотри
have Czechs like that. Well, even  V
давай так вот есть чехи Ну даже в
Transnistria is even in Transnistria, that
Приднестровье даже в Приднестровье то то
is, and Russia is simply pouring a huge amount of money from the entire
есть а Россия огромнейший деньги со всей
territory into
территории просто вливает в
Transnistria, not only there, but where
Приднестровье не не только туда а куда е
else was
там е было
Ossetia? Take the squares, the same
Осетия Возьмите площадям вот та же самая
Ossetia Abkhazia before Nestro, so they will be
Осетия Абхазия пред нестро так они будут
smaller than some Belgorod region
меньше чем какая-то Белгородская область
in  sum Yes, or there with with with in proportion to
в суме Да вот или там с с с соразмерно
yes So where is all the rest of the money look,
да Так куда все остальные деньги смотри
there is a huge amount of oil gas in all of Europe
огромнейшая там нефть газ в всей Европе
they sell oil and  they sold gas, yes, where did
продают нефть и газ продавали да да куда
all this money come from?
же все эти деньги вот получается
Little Czech Republic paid gas, oh, for gas in
маленькая Чехия платила газ э за газ в
Europe, oh, for gas in Russia, there is little
Европе ой за газ России там маленькая
Lithuania, in short, everyone, everyone paid
Литва вот короче все всес все платили
themselves, didn’t produce anything, but only Russia
сами ничего не добывали но только России
was paid from Russia, money from all over Europe
платили у России бабки со всей Европы
came Russia Europe  flourish
приходили Россия Европа процветать
said when we were in Russia yes I’m
сказал кода по были в России да Я вот
looking now Look I’m looking
сейчас смотрю Вот смотри Я вот смотрю
now I see that Russia is looking
сейчас вот я вижу что Россия смотрит
now this is a rented apartment That’s
сейчас это съёмная квартира Вот вот
right yes That is, you live in conditions
именно да То есть вы живёте в условиях
that you were able to rent yes that is  they rented
которые смогли снять да то есть сняли
these conditions. If you had
вот такие Условия были бы у Вас условия
better conditions, you would have rented a better apartment. It’s
лучше вы бы сняли лучше квартиры Это
obvious when I, for example, after
очевидно я когда например после
university. Yes, when I rented an apartment. I
университета Да когда снимал квартиру Я
also rented at first. It was like that then
тоже снимал сначала Она была такая потом
I already and then I also bought my own. Yes, because I had
я уже а потом ещё и свою купил Да потому
already started to earn normally.
что уже начал нормально зарабатывать вот
so here too, that is, you live here not
так и тут то есть вы живёте тут не
because you find it Cool This is Vintage, but
потому что вам Прикольно Это Винтаж а
because your income level does not
потому что у вас уровень доходов не
allow for more normal living
позволяет более нормальные жилищные
conditions and all this, I’m not saying that it’s
условия и всё это я же не говорю что там
bad there, but why can’t you people in Russia
плохо но почему вы люди в России не
afford better housing  I
можете позволить себе лучшие жилищные
don’t know the conditions here  The Czech Republic has better
условия не знаю вот в Чехии лучше
living conditions, better I
жилищные условия лучше
don’t know, that’s a mystery, I wouldn’t be
не знаю вот вот это загад я там не бы
cool there. And in Romania we
прикольно А в Румынии
were No, just So we’re passing through the
были Нет ну только Так проездом тоже
Ponya airport too. Well, I’ll say that you can
аэропорт Поня Ну я скажу что с вокзалом
compare a station with a train station, for example, even then
сравнить вокзал например даже то
Finland and
Финляндии и
Italy Finland is better Well, you go out, you
Италии Финляндии лучше Ну да лу выходишь
go out in  Italy to the center Well, it’s
выходишь в Италии в центр Ну красивый
such a beautiful station, it’s
вокзал такой
just there and so on,
просто там и так далее наркотики
offering drugs just like that directly, I didn’t
предлага просто так напрямую мне не
like it,
понравилось
I just see that even that Romania co
просто я смотрю что даже та Румыния ко
they say there are dumb some Romanians, gypsies
говорят там немы какие-то румыны цыгане
there  they call me names but I’m in the thousandths at the beginning of the
их там обзывают но я в тысячных в начале
thousandths We went to a
тысячных Мы ездили на соревнования по
programming competition in Romania and we lived in a
программированию в Румынию да И жили в
student dormitory campus so those
студенческом кампусе общежития так те
dormitories cannot be compared with what we have and
общежития не сравнить с тем что у нас и
you have a
у вас
dormitory, that is, a person in a dormitory who
общежитие то есть человек в общежитии
lived in a student dormitory than
жит ших уя студенческом общежития чем
For example
Вот например
I'm just
вы мне просто
interested in wealth. Yes, it is measured in
интересно богатство Да оно измеряется в
some things. Yes, wealth
каких-то вещах Да там богатство
is measured there. Yes, in monetary terms. Well,
измеряется Да в денежном эквиваленте Ну
I don't measure it. How do you measure
я не измеряю это А в чём вы измеряет
wealth? Well, the whole world has been destroyed
богатство Ну весь мир измет
kaine E what can you do in the dark What
кайне Э что Ты може заго тьме Какие
goods services bla material
товары услуги бла материальные
intangible for me for me, well,
нематериальный для меня для меня ну то
what I can afford yes For me,
что я могу себе позволить да Для меня
it’s important to me that I’m
это мне главно что мне
comfortable Well, come
комфортно Ну давай
on, I can live in such conditions,
так я могу жить в таких условиях
for example, And I can have money ago  I
например А у меня могут быть деньги агое
collect,
собира
yes, that is, look at the
да то есть смотри
hedgehog in Europe, I absolutely don’t agree with this
еже европей абсолютно не вот с этим
if you, for example, are just
согласен если ты например просто
saving so that you have an
экономишь для того чтобы там у тебя есть
investment there. You collect there, for example, either
инвестиция Ты собираешь там например или
for your personal home or
на своё личное жильё или там бизнес
you invest in a business there. Yes, absolutely  maybe Yes, you
вкладываешь Да абсолютно может быть Да
know how Europeans come, you know,
знаешь как европейцы приезжают знаешь у
they seem to have, well, I immediately see a European
них вроде ну я сразу вижу европеец
coming Well, a foreigner Damn, they have
приезжают Ну иностранец Блин у них
simple jeans, simple
простенькие джинки простенькие
T-shirts,
футболочки
they want
хотят
this ho sri, come on, not specifically those But the
этим хо сри давай так не конкретно те А
general population That is, I don’t know,
вот общее население То есть я не знаю
maybe it just depends on the people
может быть просто от людей зависит
you know, someone doesn’t want to live better and
знаешь кто-то не хочет жить лучше так и
lives just like that, you know, tries money and so
живёт просто знаешь пробует деньги и так
on And someone is trying to fence it off,
далее А кто-то ну старается огородить
it’s impossible jelly, so let’s take
это не мо желе поэтому давай так возьмём
a teacher for example  in post-Soviet
например учительницу в постсоветских
countries Yes, in the same Russia and a teacher
странах Да в той же России и учительницу
in Finland Yes, where a simple teacher
в Финляндии Да где учительница простая
Yes East Kazakhstan region
Да ВКО
can afford more material
может больше себе позволить материальных
and non-material benefits I don’t
и нематериальных благ я не
know I don’t
знаю не
know Well, I have a very simple
знаю Ну у меня есть очень простой
indicator Where is it better if people travel from
показатель Где лучше если люди едут из
one point to another and vice versa  if they don’t go, it
одной точки в другую а наоборот не едут
means it’s better at the point where they’re going.
значит лучше в той точке куда едут
For example, if Finland
Например если из России Финляндию
is being rushed from Russia for permanent residence, but if they don’t go back, that means
ломятся на ПМЖ А назад нет значит
Finland is better off. I want to
Финляндии луше
leave Russia now. And where do you want to
Россию сейчас хочу уехать А куда хотите
go? Well, I don’t know  I’ll probably think about going to Israel.
уехать Ну не знаю подумаю в Израиль
And you, with
наверно А вы ж
Transnistrian citizenship, I can
приднестровский гражданством могу
go. But I understand. So, you’re
поехать А понял Так по Вы же там
some kind of food blogger there or whoever was there, I
какой-то фудблогер или кто были там я
found you there. I’m on TV in YouTube, you
там вас нашёл Я ТБ в юбе вы там какие-то
also filmed something there, but no, I was
типа тоже снимали а нет дома
kidding myself with
прикалывался
something at home.  then I found you at the airport and
что-то какой-то аэропорт я тогда нашл
looked at your face. What were you doing?
вас по лицу посмотрел Чем вы занимались
Okay, let’s run
Хорошо давайте побегу
further. The girl there is massaging her heel,
дальше Девушку там пятку ей про
otherwise she was twitching like that,
массажирует а то она так дёргалась
let’s
давайте всё
do it like this, in short, who on earth?  zust from
давай вот так короче кого на зуст с
Transnistria won the Armed Forces against Moldova Yes,
Приднестровья воны ВС против Молдовы Да
Moldova is bad bad but everyone has a
Молдова плохая плохая но у всех есть
Moldovan passport letter to my Telegram
молдовки паспорт пись на мий Telegram
straight away he is even
прям зараз он а
more and more respectful YouTube taking us
пок дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня нас
through SR GR in the new ban and even more videos I do
через СР гр в ньй бан и дуже багато вдео
n’t show people often I don’t show
не показую людям вчасно не показуе
information  about streams for this purpose for
информация про стримы тому для того щоб
Mali operational connection  sign up
ми Мали оперативный звязок пишиться
directly for a pok there in telegra okm vdeo shche
прямо за а пок там в телегра окм вдео ще
tezh tsikava and korisna information and mi
теж цикава и корисна информация и ми
vinni z you trim postiyny
повинни з вами трима постийний
operational link
оперативный звязок
nezalezhno in that chi show you about it
незалежно в того чи покаже вам про це
YouTube Glory to Ukraine subscribe
YouTube Слава Украине подпишись